<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: This Post Won&#8217;t Go Viral	</title>
	<atom:link href="/viral/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/viral/</link>
	<description>Bring your own data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 18:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Nicholas M. Cummings		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-445186</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nicholas M. Cummings]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 18:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-445186</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;/viral/#comment-172551&quot;&gt;AdamGurri&lt;/a&gt;.

You clearly have easy, credible access to a much bigger node in the network than a lot of people.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="/viral/#comment-172551">AdamGurri</a>.</p>
<p>You clearly have easy, credible access to a much bigger node in the network than a lot of people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: AdamGurri		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-172551</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AdamGurri]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 13:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-172551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, I tweeted a link, which was retweeted by my friend, and because of that, was retweeted by his professor who follows him. His professor is Tyler Cowen, so that resulted in many people who followed HIM retweeted it/sharing the link. That&#039;s 2-3 degrees already, right? Or more?


Today, a friend of mine shared a post with me, which I shared with the friend who retweeted it yesterday. He in turn shared the link on Twitter, which Tyler Cowen saw and then linked to on Marginal Revolution.


It seems to me that either I live an extraordinarily improbable life, your study doesn&#039;t correctly capture the odds that something will jump more than one or two degrees, or I&#039;m completely misinterpreting your results.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, I tweeted a link, which was retweeted by my friend, and because of that, was retweeted by his professor who follows him. His professor is Tyler Cowen, so that resulted in many people who followed HIM retweeted it/sharing the link. That&#8217;s 2-3 degrees already, right? Or more?</p>
<p>Today, a friend of mine shared a post with me, which I shared with the friend who retweeted it yesterday. He in turn shared the link on Twitter, which Tyler Cowen saw and then linked to on Marginal Revolution.</p>
<p>It seems to me that either I live an extraordinarily improbable life, your study doesn&#8217;t correctly capture the odds that something will jump more than one or two degrees, or I&#8217;m completely misinterpreting your results.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Rethinking Information Diversity in Networks &#124; Blog de Joaquin Gonzalez		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-137736</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rethinking Information Diversity in Networks &#124; Blog de Joaquin Gonzalez]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 05:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-137736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[...] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: The Role of Social Networks in Information Diffusion &#124; Webfinds of Bas Prohn		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-137589</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The Role of Social Networks in Information Diffusion &#124; Webfinds of Bas Prohn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2012 12:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-137589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[...] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: My Blog - Rethinking Information Diversity in Networks		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-137475</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[My Blog - Rethinking Information Diversity in Networks]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 20:28:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-137475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[...] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [...]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] on Twitter by Bakshy et al. and has been studied across other networks more extensively in upcoming work by Sharad Goel and Duncan Watts at Yahoo! Research, [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Alberto		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-84306</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alberto]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2011 13:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-84306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[very interesting! Is it possible to have the paper reference??]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>very interesting! Is it possible to have the paper reference??</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Rob Paterson		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-82924</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rob Paterson]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 16:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-82924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I wonder if you may have overlooked the TRUST or closeness element? To get HIV Aids I have to have sex with another person or be born from an infected mother. To get cholera I have to drink infected water or get another&#039;s feces on me and ingest it. 

Much of the connection on Twitter etc is very superficial. BUT if a real friend of mine was excited about an idea and told me I would listen.

For instance - I have been on a Paleo diet for 9 months now. I blog a lot about it but don&#039;t push it. Many of my real friends have seen how well I am - see that they share my original risk - and now are on it too. But I have had very little luck in persuading any who are more distant. They on the other hand are having some success in persuading their other real friends...]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wonder if you may have overlooked the TRUST or closeness element? To get HIV Aids I have to have sex with another person or be born from an infected mother. To get cholera I have to drink infected water or get another&#8217;s feces on me and ingest it. </p>
<p>Much of the connection on Twitter etc is very superficial. BUT if a real friend of mine was excited about an idea and told me I would listen.</p>
<p>For instance &#8211; I have been on a Paleo diet for 9 months now. I blog a lot about it but don&#8217;t push it. Many of my real friends have seen how well I am &#8211; see that they share my original risk &#8211; and now are on it too. But I have had very little luck in persuading any who are more distant. They on the other hand are having some success in persuading their other real friends&#8230;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: David Phillips		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-82861</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Phillips]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 12:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-82861</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As someone who has been living with HIV just shy of 29 years, I find the thoughtless and ignorant re-telling of the origin of the HIV pandemic very offensive.  Specifically, you write &quot;These first clinically observed cases of AIDS, later traced back to HIV, were the start of a global pandemic that has claimed the lives of more than 25 million people to date.&quot;  Actually, that sentence is both ignorant and in conflict earlier sentences.

The cases of advanced HIV disease observed in 1981 were, in fact, the first to be clustered and presented to Western doctors who would &quot;put the pieces together,&quot; not those that began the pandemic.  The wasting effects of HIV, commonly known as &quot;slim,&quot; had already been recounted in the oral histories of sub-Saharan Africa for over two generations, particularly among female sex workers in urban brothels.  Economic conditions in Africa, driven by the hunger of colonial powers for timber, minerals, and other natural resources, drew people into urban centers early in the 20th Century as HIV was making its way from first human contact to the cities.  There, HIV found ideal hosts among local sex workers and their transient partners, men who would often carry the virus to other cities and back to smaller villages.  Unwittingly, these non-drug-using heterosexuals became the first cases of HIV disease that would spark the pandemic.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As someone who has been living with HIV just shy of 29 years, I find the thoughtless and ignorant re-telling of the origin of the HIV pandemic very offensive.  Specifically, you write &#8220;These first clinically observed cases of AIDS, later traced back to HIV, were the start of a global pandemic that has claimed the lives of more than 25 million people to date.&#8221;  Actually, that sentence is both ignorant and in conflict earlier sentences.</p>
<p>The cases of advanced HIV disease observed in 1981 were, in fact, the first to be clustered and presented to Western doctors who would &#8220;put the pieces together,&#8221; not those that began the pandemic.  The wasting effects of HIV, commonly known as &#8220;slim,&#8221; had already been recounted in the oral histories of sub-Saharan Africa for over two generations, particularly among female sex workers in urban brothels.  Economic conditions in Africa, driven by the hunger of colonial powers for timber, minerals, and other natural resources, drew people into urban centers early in the 20th Century as HIV was making its way from first human contact to the cities.  There, HIV found ideal hosts among local sex workers and their transient partners, men who would often carry the virus to other cities and back to smaller villages.  Unwittingly, these non-drug-using heterosexuals became the first cases of HIV disease that would spark the pandemic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Ben		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-82757</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ben]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 03:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-82757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Some questions that stand out, having not read any paper and so therefore obnoxiously nitpicking something sight unseen:

 * Facebook: is it reasonable to use one app&#039;s content diffusion on Facebook as a proxy for content diffusion on Facebook as a whole? I&#039;d argue that it isn&#039;t, there are different distribution channels on Facebook, different ways to implement an app, differently compelling app content, all of which should result in differing levels of &quot;virality&quot;.

Twitter:
 * Is it possible there was a large amount of spam, diluting the # of diffusion trees (because no one chose to diffuse the spam links)? What does a sampling of the studied Tweets look like?
 * Ditto, but for content that just wasn&#039;t successful - there was only one adopter of the bit.ly link (in other words - that no diffusion at all occurred).
 * What is the definition of an &quot;adoption&quot;? By &quot;the vast majority of adoptions occur either without peer-to-peer influence or within one step&quot;, do you mean that one person posts a link, someone who is not following that person reposts the link, and that constitutes an independent adoption? Or is the first posting of the bit.ly link itself an adoption, meaning that the case where two people independently post a bit.ly link = two adoptions? If so the pool of successful adoptions would be diluted by garbage content, or just un-viral content - content that had no distribution tree at all, viral or otherwise.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some questions that stand out, having not read any paper and so therefore obnoxiously nitpicking something sight unseen:</p>
<p> * Facebook: is it reasonable to use one app&#8217;s content diffusion on Facebook as a proxy for content diffusion on Facebook as a whole? I&#8217;d argue that it isn&#8217;t, there are different distribution channels on Facebook, different ways to implement an app, differently compelling app content, all of which should result in differing levels of &#8220;virality&#8221;.</p>
<p>Twitter:<br />
 * Is it possible there was a large amount of spam, diluting the # of diffusion trees (because no one chose to diffuse the spam links)? What does a sampling of the studied Tweets look like?<br />
 * Ditto, but for content that just wasn&#8217;t successful &#8211; there was only one adopter of the bit.ly link (in other words &#8211; that no diffusion at all occurred).<br />
 * What is the definition of an &#8220;adoption&#8221;? By &#8220;the vast majority of adoptions occur either without peer-to-peer influence or within one step&#8221;, do you mean that one person posts a link, someone who is not following that person reposts the link, and that constitutes an independent adoption? Or is the first posting of the bit.ly link itself an adoption, meaning that the case where two people independently post a bit.ly link = two adoptions? If so the pool of successful adoptions would be diluted by garbage content, or just un-viral content &#8211; content that had no distribution tree at all, viral or otherwise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Ewan		</title>
		<link>/viral/#comment-82661</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ewan]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 20:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1510#comment-82661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Perhaps there isn&#039;t a paper yet, but any brief description of the methodology? What does the data look like? What does the graphical model look like?]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps there isn&#8217;t a paper yet, but any brief description of the methodology? What does the data look like? What does the graphical model look like?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
