<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Scroogenomics vs Ulterior Motives (and Other Justifications for Gift Giving)	</title>
	<atom:link href="/scrooge/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/scrooge/</link>
	<description>Bring your own data</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 06:39:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: David Rutter		</title>
		<link>/scrooge/#comment-230424</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Rutter]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 06:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=552#comment-230424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&quot;the difference between what we spend on holiday gifts and what the recipients would have been willing to spend to buy those items themselves.&quot; This probably falls into #4 or #5, but there are situations where you know someone (perhaps due to income inequality or perhaps due to general stinginess) is incapable of paying as much as they might value it, and because of this, think they value it less (let us not become emotionally attached to things we might want but can&#039;t have). In particular, you know they&#039;ll love it, but also know they would never buy it.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;the difference between what we spend on holiday gifts and what the recipients would have been willing to spend to buy those items themselves.&#8221; This probably falls into #4 or #5, but there are situations where you know someone (perhaps due to income inequality or perhaps due to general stinginess) is incapable of paying as much as they might value it, and because of this, think they value it less (let us not become emotionally attached to things we might want but can&#8217;t have). In particular, you know they&#8217;ll love it, but also know they would never buy it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: dreeves		</title>
		<link>/scrooge/#comment-22327</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dreeves]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 21:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=552#comment-22327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Other inefficiencies of the season...

Sharad pointed out that “after-Christmas sale” is a euphemism for “pre-Christmas price-gouging.” This is not an inefficiency if you include the utility of the retailers but from consumers’ perspective, it’s inefficient to concentrate demand around a single day of the year. Bah humbug!

I recently encountered an inefficiency related to holiday travel. Many outbound NYC flights were canceled the weekend before Christmas due to a snowstorm. People were generally rebooked a few days later. But on Monday everything was back to normal. I know because I flew out of New York on Monday. My aunt was supposed to fly out on Saturday but got stranded until Tuesday. She clearly wanted to depart on Monday more than we did. It’s a shame that there’s essentially no secondary market for airline tickets! (Though there is in a very limited sense: You can volunteer to be bumped and the airline will compensate you with travel vouchers, worth deceptively little. But naturally the airlines are not bumping willing travelers in order to rebook people sooner when their original flights were canceled.)]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Other inefficiencies of the season&#8230;</p>
<p>Sharad pointed out that “after-Christmas sale” is a euphemism for “pre-Christmas price-gouging.” This is not an inefficiency if you include the utility of the retailers but from consumers’ perspective, it’s inefficient to concentrate demand around a single day of the year. Bah humbug!</p>
<p>I recently encountered an inefficiency related to holiday travel. Many outbound NYC flights were canceled the weekend before Christmas due to a snowstorm. People were generally rebooked a few days later. But on Monday everything was back to normal. I know because I flew out of New York on Monday. My aunt was supposed to fly out on Saturday but got stranded until Tuesday. She clearly wanted to depart on Monday more than we did. It’s a shame that there’s essentially no secondary market for airline tickets! (Though there is in a very limited sense: You can volunteer to be bumped and the airline will compensate you with travel vouchers, worth deceptively little. But naturally the airlines are not bumping willing travelers in order to rebook people sooner when their original flights were canceled.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Vincent Conitzer		</title>
		<link>/scrooge/#comment-1328</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vincent Conitzer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 23:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=552#comment-1328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think 2 (signaling value) is the big one, proving one&#039;s ability to empathize with the recipient (as well as proving effort spent on trying to empathize, which presumably has other long-term benefits for the relationship). This also explains why cash and gift cards are often seen as &quot;bad&quot; presents -- while you get $1 or $.99 of value for the dollar, it doesn&#039;t show that you understand the other&#039;s desires and needs.

Another one: sometimes you can give someone something that he will enjoy but would have been embarrassed to get for himself. E.g., if Homer buys a bowling ball for himself (not as a gift), this sends a signal to others that he cares more about bowling than about his family -- a signal he may be reluctant to send. However, if Marge buys Homer a bowling ball, Homer is &quot;off the hook&quot; -- he couldn&#039;t help getting the bowling ball, plus there is a signal that Marge thinks Homer is a good father who deserves a break, which is part of the present.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think 2 (signaling value) is the big one, proving one&#8217;s ability to empathize with the recipient (as well as proving effort spent on trying to empathize, which presumably has other long-term benefits for the relationship). This also explains why cash and gift cards are often seen as &#8220;bad&#8221; presents &#8212; while you get $1 or $.99 of value for the dollar, it doesn&#8217;t show that you understand the other&#8217;s desires and needs.</p>
<p>Another one: sometimes you can give someone something that he will enjoy but would have been embarrassed to get for himself. E.g., if Homer buys a bowling ball for himself (not as a gift), this sends a signal to others that he cares more about bowling than about his family &#8212; a signal he may be reluctant to send. However, if Marge buys Homer a bowling ball, Homer is &#8220;off the hook&#8221; &#8212; he couldn&#8217;t help getting the bowling ball, plus there is a signal that Marge thinks Homer is a good father who deserves a break, which is part of the present.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Jeff Ely		</title>
		<link>/scrooge/#comment-1325</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jeff Ely]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 16:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=552#comment-1325</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[dear dan:

of all the poser economists, you are my second-favorite. Let&#039;s pose together sometime. Happy new year. 

Jeff]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>dear dan:</p>
<p>of all the poser economists, you are my second-favorite. Let&#8217;s pose together sometime. Happy new year. </p>
<p>Jeff</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
